<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>index on Simon H Moore</title>
    <link>https://simonhugh.xyz/</link>
    <description>Recent content in index on Simon H Moore</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 23:36:28 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://simonhugh.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My First Lug Event</title>
      <link>https://simonhugh.xyz/posts/my-first-lug-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 23:36:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simonhugh.xyz/posts/my-first-lug-event/</guid>
      <description>Linux has such a large following that many cities have regular meetings between linux and open source enthusiasts called lug (Linux User Group) events, and Liverpool is no exception.
On every 1st Wednesday of every calender month a bunch of Linux enthusiasts meet at Liverpool DOES, and have a general chat or even talks and presentations over Linux and open source related topics.
On this last Wednesday I paid the Liverpool lug event a visit.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Linux has such a large following that many cities have regular meetings between linux and open source enthusiasts called &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linux_user_group&#34;&gt;lug&lt;/a&gt; (Linux User Group) events, and Liverpool is no exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On every 1st Wednesday of every calender month a bunch of Linux enthusiasts meet at &lt;a href=&#34;https://doesliverpool.com/&#34;&gt;Liverpool DOES&lt;/a&gt;, and have a general chat or even talks and presentations over Linux and open source related topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this last Wednesday I paid the &lt;a href=&#34;https://livlug.org.uk/&#34;&gt;Liverpool lug&lt;/a&gt; event a visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;about-liverpool-does&#34;&gt;About Liverpool DOES&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://doesliverpool.com/&#34;&gt;Liverpool DOES&lt;/a&gt; is a meeting space for hackers, builders, inventors and general cool guys and girls making all kinds of stuff, from the useful, to the awesome and even bizarre. If your head is full of cool ideas that just want to become reality, then this is the place to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon arriving at &lt;a href=&#34;https://doesliverpool.com/&#34;&gt;Liverpool DOES&lt;/a&gt;, I was shown around the facilities by the host of the event, and they have all kinds of cool toys, from 3d printers to laser cutters. There is no shortage of things to work with or to make interesting stuff with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I was here for linux and the only tool I need is the keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-lug-event&#34;&gt;The LUG Event&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event was about half a dozen people talking about all kinds of topics related to linux and open source, and sometimes about other topics as well, such as cars or films.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been told that usually there would be talks and presentations on interesting topics, but this &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linux_user_group&#34;&gt;lug&lt;/a&gt; event nothing was planned, nevertheless I had fun and found the evening interesting and the people friendly. If you have a passion for linux and open source, I would defiantly recommend going, and personally I will be going to the next one in May.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;about-liverpool-lug&#34;&gt;About Liverpool Lug&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Liverpool Linux User Group meets every 1st Wednesday of every calender month and anybody is welcome, it is completely free, and you will even get a cup of tea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meetings take place at &lt;a href=&#34;https://doesliverpool.com/&#34;&gt;Liverpool DOES&lt;/a&gt;, at 68-76 Kempston Street, L3 8HL. Just ring the bell and someone will buzz you in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find out more about Liverpool lug, you can visit their site &lt;a href=&#34;https://livlug.org.uk/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
And to find out more about Liverpool DOES you can visit their site &lt;a href=&#34;https://doesliverpool.com/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Made This Site</title>
      <link>https://simonhugh.xyz/posts/how-i-made-this-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 13:43:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://simonhugh.xyz/posts/how-i-made-this-site/</guid>
      <description>I have always believed in minimalism and the KISS principle, so when I wanted to make my own site and blog, I needed something that followed these ideals.
Hugo to the rescue!
How does hugo work? Hugo is a static site generator written in Go, it is incredibly easy to set up and get going and you can write your content in plain old markdown. Hugo then takes you content/posts/blogs written in markdown and compiles them to html with a beautiful theme.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I have always believed in minimalism and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/KISS_principle&#34;&gt;KISS&lt;/a&gt; principle, so when I wanted to make my own site and blog, I needed something that followed these ideals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; to the rescue!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-does-hugo-work&#34;&gt;How does hugo work?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; is a static site generator written in &lt;a href=&#34;https://go.dev/&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt;, it is incredibly easy to set up and get going and you can write your content in plain old markdown. &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; then takes you content/posts/blogs written in markdown and compiles them to html with a beautiful theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To use &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;hugo&lt;/a&gt;, you first need to install it, you can find the official documentation to do so &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/installation/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, but if you are using linux, it will most likely be available in your distributions package manager, and on windows you can us &lt;a href=&#34;https://scoop.sh/&#34;&gt;scoop&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://chocolatey.org/&#34;&gt;chocolatey&lt;/a&gt; to install &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;hugo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; is installed, follow the &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;quickstart&lt;/a&gt; to create a site and pick and install a hugo theme (of course you can make your own if you whish).
You can search for hugo themes on their official website &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After which it is as easy as creating some markdown files in the content folder and write about anything you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: its best to create the markdown files with the command &lt;code&gt;hugo new NAME-OF-FILE&lt;/code&gt; as hugo will generate the appropriate metadata in the file for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; comes with a inbuilt development server to preview your content, just run &lt;code&gt;hugo server&lt;/code&gt; inside your sites root directory and then, in your browser, navigate to &lt;code&gt;http://localhost:1313&lt;/code&gt; (the port might be different if &lt;code&gt;1313&lt;/code&gt; is occupied, check the output of the command for the uri address).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you are happy with how your site looks and its content, simply run the &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; command inside your sites root directory and it will compile the site and generate all necessary files inside the &lt;code&gt;public&lt;/code&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can then host the &lt;code&gt;public&lt;/code&gt; directory with your preferred web server such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nginx.com/&#34;&gt;nginx&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;github-pages&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One easy and simple way to host your website for free is to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;&gt;github pages&lt;/a&gt;, this is what I did for my site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the advantages of &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;&gt;github pages&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;its very easy to set up and maintain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you can use &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; to update your website, simple commit your latest changes and push them to the repository.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;its free.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there are some disadvantages using &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;&gt;github pages&lt;/a&gt;, such as that it has minimal support for dynamic content and no support for server side code. But that is ok, since we are using &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;hugo&lt;/a&gt;, a static site generator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do so simply create a repository on your github account called &lt;code&gt;USERNAME.github.io&lt;/code&gt; (where &lt;code&gt;USERNAME&lt;/code&gt; is the username of your github account) and push the contents of the &lt;code&gt;public&lt;/code&gt; folder inside your hugo site to said repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can then access your github page by navigating to &lt;code&gt;USERNAME.github.io&lt;/code&gt; in your browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;i-want-to-use-my-own-domain&#34;&gt;I want to use my own domain&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As cool as &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;&gt;github pages&lt;/a&gt; is, it would be even cooler if you could use your own domain such as &lt;code&gt;simonhugh.xyz&lt;/code&gt;, and you can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All you need to do is purchase a domain from a domain register and create 4 new &lt;code&gt;A records&lt;/code&gt; for the domain and set each to one of the four github IP addresses listed below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;- 185.199.108.153
- 185.199.109.153
- 185.199.110.153
- 185.199.111.153
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find more help on how to do this by following the official github instructions &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.github.com/en/pages/configuring-a-custom-domain-for-your-github-pages-site/managing-a-custom-domain-for-your-github-pages-site&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you have done that, navigate to your &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;&gt;github pages&lt;/a&gt; repository and navigate to setting -&amp;gt; pages and enter your domain in the &lt;code&gt;custom domain&lt;/code&gt; field. Github will then verify that you DNS is set up properly, once it has, you should be able to view your &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;&gt;github pages&lt;/a&gt; website by navigating to your custom domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: if it does not work, you might need to wait a while since it can take up to 48 hours to propagate the changes you made to your domains &lt;code&gt;A records&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
